Finding Aid for Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union records, 1874-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union records
1874-2006
Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union.
85596 Bj 2
State chapter of national temperance organization founded in 1874; records include correspondence of early W.C.T.U. workers, Alice E. H. Peters and Ella Eaton Kellogg; also minutes, scrapbooks, and other records of individual Michigan W.C.T.U. districts and chapters.
16 linear feet in 17 boxes
3 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This record group (donor 5688 ) was first deposited with the library in 1975. Additional records have been received.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
With the assistance and encouragement of an Ohio women's temperance union, local Michigan women's temperance groups met in Lansing in February 1874 for the purpose of forming a state organization of their own. Later in 1874 this organization took the name Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU). The group's main purpose was to work for the outlawing of liquor sales in the state of Michigan. Like other burgeoning state organizations, the Michigan WCTU was organized in part to assist in the formation of local unions which would then mobilize grass-roots support for various prohibition legislation and local option campaigns. In addition, their membership campaigned for woman suffrage and protective legislation for women and children.
The WCTU's greatest influence was in the years leading up to the passage of the eighteenth amendment. With the repeal of this amendment in 1933, the organization lost much of its focus. While continuing to support prohibition legislation, the organization also began to stress education campaigns about related issues, such as drug abuse and drunken driving. By the early 1970s many unions were disbanding because of declining membership and lack of interest; this trend continued through the 1980s and 1990s, although the WCTU continued its work of educating the public about alcohol and drug abuse.
For more detailed histories of the Michigan WCTU, the researcher should consult A Brief History of Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union, compiled by Mrs. J.P. Howard and Mrs. Julia R. Parish (1912) and Guide to the Microfilm Edition of Temperance and Prohibition Papers, edited by Randall C. Jimerson, Francis X. Blouin and Charles A. Isetts (1977).
The Michigan Woman's Temperance Union records divide into seven series: Correspondence; Miscellaneous and Publicity; Printed Materials; District Records; County Union Records; Local Union Records; and Photographs. The records document the period of the Michigan WCTU's greatest influence, the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, as well as the organization's gradual declining influence following the repeal of the prohibition amendment.
Subjects:
Coats Grove (Mich.); Dowagiac (Mich.); Eaton County (Mich.); Genesee County (Mich.); Grand Rapids (Mich.); La Salle (Mich.); Macomb County (Mich.); North Adams (Mich.); Social reformers--Michigan.; Swartz Creek (Mich.); Temperance--Michigan.; Vassar (Mich.); Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Coats Grove.Coats Grove.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Dowagiac.MichiganDowagiac.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Eaton County.Eaton County.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Genesee County.MichiganGenesee County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Grand Rapids.MichiganGrand Rapids.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--La Salle.MichiganLa Salle.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Macomb County.MichiganMacomb County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--North Adams.MichiganNorth Adams.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan.Michigan.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Swartz Creek.MichiganSwartz Creek.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Vassar.Vassar.Michigan; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; Allegan County (Mich.); Alma (Mich.); Bad Axe (Mich.); Barry County (Mich.); Boyne City (Mich.); Branch County (Mich.); Bronson (Mich.); Buchanan (Mich.); Calhoun County (Mich.); Cass County (Mich.); Columbiaville (Mich.); Coopersville (Mich.); Copemish (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Drayton Plains (Mich.); East Lansing (Mich.); Easton (Mich.); Flushing (Mich.); Fremont (Mich.); Gratiot County (Mich.); Hastings (Mich.); Highland Park (Mich.); Hillsdale (Mich.); Holland (Mich.); Huron County (Mich.); Ingham County (Mich.); Ionia (Mich.); Ithaca (Mich.); Kalamazoo (Mich.); Kent County (Mich.); Lansing (Mich.); Livingston County (Mich.); Marlette (Mich.); Menominee (Mich.); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Monroe County (Mich.); Mount Clemens (Mich.); Muskegon County (Mich.); Nashville (Mich.); Niles (Mich.); Oakland County (Mich.); Oceana County (Mich.); Otsego (Mich.); Owosso (Mich.); Petoskey (Mich.); Pickford (Mich.); Pontiac (Mich.); Portage (Mich.); Redford (Detroit, Mich.); Saint Louis (Mich.); Shiawassee County (Mich.); Willard (Mich.); Williamston (Mich.); Woodland (Mich.); Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Alma.Alma.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Bad Axe.Bad Axe.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Barry County.MichiganBarry County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Big Prairie.Big Prairie.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Boyne City.MichiganBoyne City.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Branch County.MichiganBranch County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Buchanan.Buchanan.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Bronson.MichiganBronson.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Calhoun County.Calhoun County.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Cass County.MichiganCass County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Columbiaville.Columbiaville.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Coopersville.MichiganCoopersville.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Copemish.MichiganCopemish.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Detroit.MichiganDetroit.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Drayton Plains.MichiganDrayton Plains.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--East Lansing.MichiganEast Lansing.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Easton.Easton.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Flushing.MichiganFlushing.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Fremont.MichiganFremont.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Gratiot County.MichiganGratiot County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Hastings.MichiganHastings.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Hillsdale.Hillsdale.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Holland.Holland.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Huron County.MichiganHuron County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Ingham County.MichiganIngham County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Ionia.MichiganIonia.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Ithaca.MichiganIthaca.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Kalamazoo.MichiganKalamazoo.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Kent County.MichiganKent County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Lansing.MichiganLansing.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Livingston County.MichiganLivingston County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Marlette.MichiganMarlette.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Menominee.MichiganMenominee.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Monroe County.MichiganMonroe County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Mount Clemens.MichiganMount Clemens.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Muskegon County.MichiganMuskegon County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Nashville.MichiganNashville.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Newaygo.MichiganNewaygo.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Niles.MichiganNiles.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Oakland County.MichiganOakland County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Oceana County.MichiganOceana County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Otsego.MichiganOtsego.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Owosso.MichiganOwosso.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Petoskey.MichiganPetoskey.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Pickford.MichiganPickford.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Pontiac.Pontiac.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Portage.MichiganPortage.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Sanilac County.MichiganSanilac County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Shiawassee County.Shiawassee County.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Saint Louis.MichiganSaint Louis.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Washtenaw County.MichiganWashtenaw County.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Willard.MichiganWillard.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Williamston.Williamston.Michigan; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Woodland.MichiganWoodland.; Woman's Christian Temperance Union--Michigan--Ypsilanti.MichiganYpsilanti.
Contributors:
Gordon, Anna Adams, 1853-1931.; Kellogg, E. E. (Ella Ervilla); Peters, Alice E. H.; Willard, Frances E. (Frances Elizabeth), 1839-1898.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  Correspondence (0.5 linear ft.; 1886-1967) contains letters between Michigan WCTU founders and national WCTU leaders, including Frances Willard and Anna Gordon. The series also contains correspondence regarding financial and legal matters dating from the 1960s.
  - Kellogg, E.E., 1886-1891; undated; 14 folders (Box 1)
  - Peters, Alice H., 1888-1891; undated; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Legal and Financial Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Mrs. Jennie Roberts (Deerfield Union) to Anna Gordon, 1924 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous and Publicity
  Miscellaneous and Publicity (0.3 linear ft.; 1915-1974) consists of scrapbooks, song sheets, lecture notes and award certificates, which were produced to promote and publicize the WCTU cause.
  - Clippings, 1940-1974; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Lecture Series: "The History and Philosophy of the Temperance Movement", undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notebook and program calendar (Box 1)
  - Rededication of Children's Temperance Fountain, Belle Isle, 1963 (Box 1)
    (include photographs)
  - Ruby Norman Ludwig (Central Union, Lansing)
    - Scrapbook, circa 1939-1957; 6 folders (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous printed material from Ludwig scrapbook, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - State Leaders Scrapbook, 1928-1955 (Volume 1)
  - State Membership and Award Certificates, 1915-1957 (Box 1)
  - Temperance Song Sheets and Music, undated (Box 1)
- Printed Materials
  Printed Materials (0.2 linear feet; 1892-2007, most undated) contains pamphlets, brochures, periodicals and hymnals. The series demonstrates the scope and dramatic approach of WCTU literature, much of which takes the form of testimonials.
  - Membership Directory, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets and Brochures, 3 folders
    - Capitol Report, vol. 6, no. 11 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Kawaiahao Church: Westminster Abbey of Honolulu Hawaii, Founded April 25, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Michigan Woman's Christian Temperance Union: 16mm Sound Motion Pictures [in the] State Film Library (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Prohibition Camp: Royal Templars of Temperance (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Quiz on National Constitutional Prohibition Committee of the National WCTU Convention (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sound the Jubilee (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Woman's Christian Temperance Union "For God and Home in Every Land (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Union Signal Frances Willard issue scrapbooks, 1946-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alcohol- An Aid or a Menace? (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alcohol Education in the Church: Purpose and Aim (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aldrich, Maude M.
      - The Silver Screen and the WCTU: What We Are Working for in the Motion Picture Department, and Why (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Standards for Better Motion Pictures (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allen, Dr. Len M. No Place for Alcohol in Medicine (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Armor, Mary Harris "Have I Not Commanded Thee?" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Boole, Ella A. Continuing Need for the WCTU (revised and first editions) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bourdeau-Sisco, MD, P.S. Alcohol and Syphilis (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Braude, Judge J.M. The Way of the Bad Boy (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bro, Marguerite H. Take a Stand- Not a Chance (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Burger, Nelle G.
      - In Memory's Lane (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - We Will Not Quit Until the Liquor Traffic Quits (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Does Life Begin at Twelve? (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Dozen Gains in a Dozen Years (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Emerson, Dr. Haven Alcohol - Man's Dearest Health Hazard (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ethyl Can't Come to My House! (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - For the Woman Who Thinks (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hardleigh, Homer "Prejudiced" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hudson, Mrs. Grant M. What is Christian Citizenship: Plan of Work, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "I Bet You-" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Importance of Prayer as Evidenced by the Practice of Christ (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Influence of One Good Mother (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ingvor, Sven Is Alcohol a Medicine? (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kerton, Dr. J.W. "Buy Your Own Cherries!" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lee, Edith F. The Restoration of the Home (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Masted, Rev. L.L. Why I Practice Temperance (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Menace of Marihuana (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Michigan WCTU (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mudge, E.H.
      - Cures for Drunken Driving (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Is the Legalized Liquor Traffic Really Legal? (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - John Barleycorn at His Best (Or Worst) (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - The Man in the Street (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - The "Why" of Prohibition (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - The "Why" of Repeal (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Munns, Margaret C. Carry On (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals
    - White Ribbon Bulletin (Box 1)
  - Hymnals
    - Everybody Sing: Songs of the Woman's Christian Temperance Union, 1st and 5th editions, by Anna A. Gordon, 1924 (Box 1)
    - The Temperance Songbook, by Emmet Coleman, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Voice of Song, by the National WCTU, undated (Box 1)
    - White Ribbon Hymnal, by Anna A. Gordon, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Union Signal (various issues) (Box 1)
- District Records
  District Records (2.5 linear ft.; 1888-1982) contain minutes of district annual conventions, secretary's books, scrapbooks and treasurer's books. The series includes some records for most of the eighteen WCTU district organizations.
  - District Account Ledger Books, 1957-1962 (Box 2)
  - Second District
    - Annual Convention Minutes
      - 1891-1898, 2 volumes (Box 2)
      - 1921-1954, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Third District
    - Secretary's Book, 1945-1982 (Box 2)
  - Fourth District
    - Annual Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1957 (Box 2)
    - Membership Lists, 1958-1959; 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Programs and Fliers, 1944-1963 (Box 2)
    - Speech Contests, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - Treasurer's Book, 1955-1982 (Box 2)
  - Fifth District
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1943-1974 (Box 2)
    - Annual Meeting Books, 1897; 1903 (Box 2)
  - Sixth District
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1930-1945 (Box 2)
    - District Records, 1888-1929; 2 volumes (Box 3)
    - History and Scrapbook, 1910-1952 (Box 3)
    - Secretary's Books, 1922-1954; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Seventh District
    - Minutes, 1916-1963; 3 volumes (Box 3)
    - Programs of Annual Conventions (incomplete), 1936-1961 (Box 3)
  - Ninth District
    - Correspondence, with List of Secretaries, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Secretary's Book, 1941-1950 (Box 3)
  - Tenth District Annual Convention Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Eleventh District Annual Convention Minutes, 1893-1922 (Box 3)
  - Eleventh District (Lower) Annual Convention Minutes, 1923-1982 (Box 3)
  - Eleventh District (Upper) Annual Convention Minutes, 1921-1975; 2 volumes (Box 4)
  - Twelfth District
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1916-1963; 4 volumes (Box 4)
    - Convention Register, 1942-1965 (Box 4)
    - Reports and Convention Programs, 1927-1963 (Box 4)
  - Thirteenth District Treasurer's Books, 1938-1963; 5 volumes (Box 4)
  - Fifteenth/ Sixteenth/ Seventeenth Districts Clippings and Constitution, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Sixteenth District Annual Convention Minutes, 1933-1951 (Box 4)
  - Seventeenth District Secretary's Book, 1965-1969 (Box 4)
  - Eighteenth District Treasurer's Book, 1953-1963 (Box 4)
- County Records
  County Union Records (3 linear ft.; 1883-1981) contain meeting minutes, secretary's books, membership lists, scrapbooks and treasurer's books. The series documents the day to day activities of WCTU and the coordinating role of county organizations from all over Michigan. The series is arranged alphabetically by county.
  - Allegan County
    - Convention Programs and Clippings, 1944-1952 (Box 4)
    - Recording Secretary's Book, 1934-1968 (Box 4)
  - Barry County
    - Recording Secretary's Notebooks, 1963-1974 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Branch County
    - Clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 4)
    - Membership Lists, 1958-1976 (Box 4)
    - Programs (incomplete), 1914-1975 (Box 4)
    - Secretary's Notes, 1975-1981 (Box 4)
  - Calhoun County Convention Minutes, 1928-1953 (Box 4)
  - Cass County
    - Secretary's Book, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Treasurer's Book, 1963-1973 (Box 5)
  - Eaton County
    - Account Book, 1888-1942 (Box 5)
    - Minutes, 1921-1960 (Box 5)
  - Genesee County
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1883-1954; 3 volumes (Box 5)
    - Annual Convention Program, 1929 (Box 5)
    - Record Book, 1953-1970 (Box 5)
    - Scrapbooks, circa 1940-1941; 2 volumes (Box 16)
    - Secretary's Book, 1915-1924 (Box 5)
  - Gratiot County Treasurer's Book and Clippings, 1943-1977 (Box 5)
  - Hillsdale County Scrapbooks
    - 1952-1978 (Box 5)
    - 1960s-1970s (Box 5)
  - Huron-Tuscola County Annual Convention Members List, 1960-1976 (Box 5)
  - Ingham County
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1906-1962 (Box 6)
    - Banner with slogan "For God, Home and Every Land 1890", fabric (Box 6)
    - Members Lists, 1948-1974 (Box 6)
    - Secretary's Book, 1962-1974 (Box 6)
  - Kent County
    - Correspondence and Financial Records, 1930-1936 (Box 6)
    - Minute Books, 1899-1904; 1913-1934 (Box 6)
  - Livingston County
    - Notes, 1951; undated (Box 6)
    - Secretary's Books, 1903-1967; 2 volumes (Box 6)
  - Macomb County Treasurer's Records, 1944-1958; 2 volumes (Box 6)
  - Monroe County Minutes, 1937-1947 (Box 6)
  - Muskegon County Secretary's Books, 1957-1977; 4 volumes (Box 6)
  - Oakland County Minute Books, 1917-1922; 1965-1975 (Box 6)
  - Oceana County Secretary's Book, 1965-1971 (Box 6)
  - Shiawassee County
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1924-1940 (Box 7)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 7)
    - Treasurer's Book, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - Shiawassee County, Bennington Union Secretary's Books, 1935-1959; 7 volumes (Box 7)
  - Shiawassee County, Clinton Union
    - Minutes, 1915-1921; 3 volumes (Box 7)
    - Treasurer's Books, 1928-1970; 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - Shiawassee County, Corunna Union Secretary's Books, 1952-1962; 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - Tuscola and Huron Counties Minute Book, 1959-1976 (Box 7)
- Local Union Records
  Local Union Records (9.5 linear ft.; 1874-1991) contain meeting minutes, secretary's books, membership lists, scrapbooks and treasurer's books. The series documents the day to day activities of WCTU at the community level from all over Michigan. Included are substantial records for Grand Rapids and Owosso chapters. The Owosso records contain minutes which date back to 1874, the year of the Michigan WCTU's founding.
  - Alma
    - Annual Convention Minutes, 1894-1898 (Box 7)
    - Secretary's Books, 1950-1953; 1968; 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - Bad Axe Secretary's Book, 1965-1968 (Box 7)
  - Big Prairie
    - Secretary's Book, 1908-1914 (Box 7)
    - Secretary's Notes, circa 1899-1909 (Box 7)
  - Boyne City
    - Record Books, 1955-1984; 3 volumes (Box 7)
    - Scrapbook, 1977-1985 (Volume 2)
  - Bronson Secretary's Book, 1965-1972 (Box 8)
  - Buchanan Scrapbook, 1933-1945 (Box 8)
  - Coats Grove
    - Minute Books (some gaps), 1887-1921; 6 volumes (Box 17)
    - Historical notes (Box 17)
  - Columbiaville
    - Annual Convention Member List, 1963-1978 (Box 8)
    - Treasurer's Books, 1961-1978; 2 volumes (Box 8)
  - Coopersville
    - Ledgers, 1938-1955 (Box 8)
    - Programs, 1909-1945 (Box 8)
    - Scrapbook, circa 1950 (Box 8)
    - Secretary's Books, 1923-1987; 9 volumes (Box 8)
  - Copemish Minutes, 1937-1943 (Box 8)
  - Detroit Federation
    - Secretary's Books, 1959-1965; 3 volumes (Box 8)
    - Yearbooks, 1945-1960 (Box 8)
  - Dowagiac
    - Minute Book, 1886-1889 (Box 8)
    - Record Book and Ledger, 1954-1986 (Box 8)
  - Drayton Plains
    - Scrapbook, 1938-1943 (Volume 3)
    - Secretary's Books, 1941-1981; 9 volumes (Box 9)
  - Easton Secretary's Books, 1915-1954; 3 volumes (Box 9)
  - Flushing-Flint
    - Devotional Books, circa 1948-1953 (Box 9)
    - Minute Books, 1933-1969; 3 volumes (Box 9)
  - Fremont Treasurer's Book, 1942-1953 (Box 9)
  - Grand Rapids
    - Federation Minutes, 1963-1988 (Box 9)
    - History, undated (Box 9)
    - Minutes, 1884-1885 (Box 9)
    - Scrapbook, 1959-1976 (Box 9)
  - Grand Rapids Central Union
    - Meeting Minutes, 1950-1960; 1980-1989; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Record Books, 1947-1968; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Treasurer's Books, 1955-1989 (Box 10)
  - Grand Rapids South Union Minutes, 1884-1971; 9 volumes; 1 folders (Box 10)
  - Grand Rapids West Side Minutes, 1969-1991 (Box 10)
  - Grenville Minutes, 1952-1979 (Box 10)
  - Hastings
    - History, undated (Box 10)
    - Secretary's Book, 1959-1969 (Box 10)
  - Hillsdale
    - Convention Pamphlets and Constitution, 1927-1932 (Box 11)
    - Minute Books, 1961-1978 (Box 11)
    - Programs, 1917-1967 (Box 11)
    - Records Books, 1898-1989; 3 volumes (Box 11)
  - Holland
    - Programs and Financial Records, 1916-1970 (Box 11)
    - Treasurer's Books, 1916-1953; 2 volumes (Box 11)
    - Intercity Council of East Lansing Minutes, 1960-1974 (Box 11)
  - Ionia
    - Minute Books, 1943-1978; 4 volumes (Box 11)
    - Programs, Membership Lists and Correspondence, 1945-1980 (Box 11)
    - Roll Call Books, 1945-1961 (Box 11)
  - Ithaca Minute Books, 1929-1953; 3 volumes (Box 12)
  - Kalamazoo Secretary's Book, 1933-1942 (Box 12)
  - Kalkaska minutes book and miscellaneous, 1954-1956 (Box 12)
  - La Salle scrapbook, 1964-1970 (Box 12)
  - Lake Odessa Minute Book, 1957-1963 (Box 12)
  - Lansing Minutes, 1937-1948; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Lansing Central Union
    - Histories, 1947; undated (Box 12)
    - Minute Books, 1917-1925; 1961-1972; 4 volumes (Box 12)
  - Lansing Iota Sigma Chapter Minutes, circa 1943-1945 (Box 12)
  - Marlette Minutes, 1955-1973; 7 volumes (Box 12)
  - Mary T. Lathrop Chapter Minutes, 1937-1976; 3 volumes (Box 12)
  - Menominee Minute Books, 1945-1978; 7 volumes (Box 12)
  - Mt. Clemens
    - Correspondence, 1919-1936 (Box 13)
    - Financial and Membership Records, 1925-1940 (Box 13)
    - Minute Books, 1916-1941; 4 volumes (Box 13)
  - Nashville Minutes, 1946-1987 (Box 13)
  - Niles
    - Membership Lists and Clippings, 1953-1959 (Box 13)
    - Secretary's Book, 1960 (Box 13)
  - North Adams
    - Minute book, 1902-1908 (Box 17)
    - Minute book, 1916-1935 (Box 17)